Guide to the Michael Kahn Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- July 1998 Acquisition, 1943-1999; 3; 27.95; (32 boxes)
  - Audiovisual Material, 1985-1987
    - Audiocassettes
      Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - The Devil's Disciple, by George Bernard Shaw, produced by L. A. Theatre Works., 1996; 1; 01:27:19 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394685)
      - Jerzy Sapieyevski, undated; 1; 00:23:27 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394693)
      - Louis Rosen, Theatre Music, 1987; 1; 00:23:07 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394701)
      - Michael Kahn. Interview #6, one side, 1990 June 25; 1; 00:38:22; A high amount of background noise and hum can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394719)
      - Mother Courage, music by "Milhaud, Dessau and Eisler", undated; 1; 00:34:50; The program is distorted at times. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394727)
      - Mother Courage -in French, one side, undated; 1; 00:17:47; Static, clicks and pops can be heard on the tape. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394735)
        Contents are listed below.
        1. "Song of Mother Courage"
        2. "Song of Fraternization"
        3. "March of Victory"
        4. "Song of Solomon"
        5. "Lullabye"
        6. "Song of the Great Capitulation"
      - Much Ado About Nothing QA, undated; 1; 00:03:02 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394743)
      - Music by Adam Wernick, 3 short excerpts from "Komachi," Three Poets, undated; 1; 00:10:15 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394750)
      - RNT: NPR and Rerun, TISH Rae, undated; 1; 00:18:09; The program ends abruptly. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394768)
      - Rehearsal Show Tape, undated; 1; 00:34:48 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394776)
      - Shakespeare Theatre Salute, "Soundbites", undated; 1; 00:17:10; A high amount of background noise and static can be heard on the tape. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394784)
      - Three short excerpts from "Komachi", undated; 1; 00:13:04; Extensive breaks at times between songs and takes. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394792)
      - The Trial of Hamlet. National Public Radio's Morning Edition, 1994 March 26; 1; 00:22:53; Static can be heard on the tape. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394800)
      - Volpone Session Tape, Catherine MacDonald, 1996 April 8; 1; 00:18:17; Extensive breaks at times between songs and takes. (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394818)
      - "WGMS/Kahn," Cole and Weber, The Boeing Company, 1995 December 21; 1; 00:02:02 (Box 71, Item barcode 39002091394826)
    - Videocassettes
      - Acting Company Promo, undated; YCALMSS789_0001; 1; 00:23:22 (Box 72, Item barcode 39002102349447)
      - Carmen, undated; YCALMSS789_0002; 1; 02:40:09 (Box 72, Item barcode 39002102349454)
      - Henry V afterwords by Michael Kahn at Shakespeare Theatre; Lobby; King Lear by Stewart Johnson; a walk along 7th Street and Pennsylvania Avenue filmed by Ruth Pierce, 1996 January 14; YCALMSS789_0003; 1; 00:34:34 (Box 72, Item barcode 39002102349462)
        A handwritten note accompanying this tape reads: Michael - Ms. Pierce gave me this video of your "Henry V" afterwords at the recent "All's Well" one. This copy is for you to keep. Peter
      - Jeff Zinn-demo tape, 1989-1990; YCALMSS789_0004; 1; 00:49:37 (Box 72, Item barcode 39002102349470)
        Contents: 1. Scenes from Buried Child produced at Wellfleet Harbor Actors Theatre (W.H.A.T.), August 1989, 2. Scenes from The Stronger, leading into "Talk To Me Like The Rain," produced as a project of the Art Institute. 3. Scenes from Goose and Tomtom, produced at W.H.A.T. in 1988; 4. Scene from "The Killer," Art Institute project, January 1990.
      - Lynn Redgrave - Working Woman, undated; YCALMSS789_0005; 1 (Box 72, Item barcode 39002102349488)
      - Michael Kahn Interview, Around Town Show #1202, 1996 October 16-17; YCALMSS789_0006; 1; 00:33:17 (Box 72, Item barcode 39002102349496)
      - Mother Courage, The Greenroom with Mick Baker, 1993; YCALMSS789_0007; 1; 00:20:13 (Box 72, Item barcode 39002102349504)
      - "Much Ado," Shakespeare segment from NHJL, 1997 January 23; YCALMSS789_0008; 1; 00:21:16 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002102349512)
        A handwritten note included with the tape reads: Michael - I sent two copies to Joe as well so that people at Juilliard can see the piece. Susan
      - "Stages of Drama with Michael Kahn and Emily Mann", undated; YCALMSS789_0009; 1; 00:25:45; A 'snowy' picture appears at the end of the video. (Box 73, Item barcode 39002102349520)
      - "Trial of Hamlet", undated; YCALMSS789_0010; 1; 02:11:57 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002102349561)
      - "To Form a More Perfect Union," demonstration pilot from WITF, undated; YCALMSS789_0011; 1; 00:14:35 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002102349546)
      - Unidentified, undated; YCALMSS789_0012; 1; 00:54:05 (Box 73, Item barcode 39002102349553)
        Contains address label of Emery Battis of Washington, D.C.
      - Henry IV. Part 1 (BBC Shakespeare], 1989; 1 (Box 72)
      - Henry IV. Part 1 (English Shakespeare Company), 1990; 1 (Box 72)
      - Henry IV. Part 2 (English Shakespeare Company), 1990; 1 (Box 72)
      - Persuasive Speaking, Esquire Success production, 1985; 1 (Box 73)
  - Printed Material, 1992-1993
    - Architecture magazine, 1992 April (Box 74)
    - The World and I magazine, 1992 September (Box 74)
    - The Theatrical Imagination [textbook], 1993 (Box 74)
  - Oversize, 1951, 1994
    - Life magazine, 1951 Dec 17 (Box 75 (Oversize))
    - Poster: Michael Kahn, Distinguished Visitor in Residence, Mary Washington College, 1994 (Box 75 (Oversize))
- January 2008 Acquisition, 1991-2006; 4; 1.83; (3 boxes)
  Correspondence, subject files, appointment books, and other files relating primarily to Michael Kahn's work at the Juilliard School.
  - The Acting Company, 1991-1996 (Box 76)
  - The Actors Center, 1996 (Box 76)
  - Alumni Notes, The Juilliard School, 1997 (Box 76)
  - Appointment books, 1995-2006; 8 (Box 76)
  - Berkshire Theatre Festival, 1995 (Box 76)
  - British American Drama Academy, 1994-1996 (Box 76)
  - Le Comte Du Nouy Foundation, 1995-2007 (Box 76)
  - The Director's Project, The Drama League, 1994 (Box 76)
  - Frank Donnelly, correspondence, 1995 (Box 76)
  - Faculty biographies, 1997 (Box 76)
  - Fax cover sheets for The Juilliard School Drama Division, undated (Box 76)
  - The Fox Foundation (Box 76)
    Includes correspondence, clippings and related papers
  - Guare and McNally, research information, clippings, 1993-1996 (Box 76)
  - Housing and hotels, undated (Box 76)
  - Felix Ivanov, 1995 (Box 76)
  - The Juilliard School, 1992-1996; 4 (Box 76)
    Includes clippings, correspondence, Alumni notes, and related papers.
  - The Juilliard School, 1993-1995; 4 (Box 77)
  - Krakow Conference: Summer, 1996 (Box 77)
  - Student self-evaluation papers, 1993-1995; 3 (Box 77)
  - Student comments, 1999-2005; 4 (Box 77)
  - Theatre Guild Hall - John Drew, 1994 (Box 77)
  - Juilliard School correspondence, 1999-2003; 6 (Box 78)
- June 2008 Acquisition, 1992-2004; 5; 1.42; (2 boxes)
  Includes correspondence, subject files, printed material and other papers relating primarily to Michael Kahn's work at the Juilliard School.
  - Appointments, 1992-1993 (Box 79)
  - The Dakota apartment, 1993-1996 (Box 79)
  - Dallas Opera, 1994 (Box 79)
  - Daniela Fischerova's New York visit, 1992-1993 (Box 79)
  - Fulbright - Keti Dolidze, 2004 (Box 79)
  - Hamlet, 1992-1993 (Box 79)
  - Helen Hayes Award, 1996-1997 (Box 79)
  - The Juilliard School, 1993-1998; 2 (Box 79)
  - Lincoln Center Repertory, 1995 (Box 79)
  - Middle States report and update, 1997 (Box 79)
  - Alan Schneider, Director's Fund, 1997 (Box 79)
  - Shakespeare Theatre, 1993-1995; 2 (Box 79)
  - Trinity College, Hartford, 1995-1997 (Box 79)
  - Theatre of the Learned Monkey, 1995 (Box 79)
  - Washington Opera clippings, 1995 (Box 79)
  - Photographs of Michael Kahn, undated (Box 79)
  - Personal Expenses, 1993-1997 (Box 79)
  - Student papers and correspondence, 1999 (Box 79)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1995; 11 (Box 79)
  - Correspondence, 1993-2000; 5 (Box 80)
  - Kraemer, Joe [Kahn's assistant at the Juilliard School], 1992-1996; 7 (Box 80)
- November 2013 Acquisition, 1995-2013; 6; 2.21; (3 boxes)
  - Correspondence (Non-Artists), 2005-2008; 2 folders (Box 81)
  - Correspondence (Artists), 2006-2012; 2 folders (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 2010 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 2010-2011 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 2010-2012 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 81)
  - Correspondence, 2011-2013 (Box 82)
  - Personal / Private Correspondence, 2006-2008; 2 folders (Box 82)
  - Personal Letters /Thank Yous, 2008-2011; 2 folders (Box 82)
  - Invitations, 2007-2008 (Box 82)
  - Invitations, 2007-2012 (Box 82)
  - Electronic media (Box 83)
    Digital media: Restricted fragile material. Access copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.